const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 4-year-old boy is brought by his parents with the complaint that he frequently catches a cold and gets cough. According to the parents, he had pneumonia thrice this year and had to be admitted to the hospital one time. On examination, an ejection systolic murmur is heard on the left upper sternal border with a fixed splitting of the second heart sound. The first heart sound is loud. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cystic fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":true},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"'Sign of 3' is a feature of which congenital disease of the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Persistent truncus arteriosus","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following pathologies is an indication for coronary artery bypass graft (CABG)?","answers":[{"option":"Valvular disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Multivessel disease","bool":true},{"option":"Right-to-left shunt","bool":false},{"option":"Left-to-right shunt","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which vasculitis involves the aorta?","answers":[{"option":"Behcet disease","bool":false},{"option":"Polyarteritis nodosa","bool":false},{"option":"Giant cell arteritis","bool":false},{"option":"Takayasu disease","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the length of nasogastric tube that should be inserted during gastric lavage?","answers":[{"option":"50 cm","bool":true},{"option":"30 cm","bool":false},{"option":"20 cm","bool":false},{"option":"35 cm","bool":false},{"option":"40 cm","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following should not be used as an antidote for sulphuric acid?","answers":[{"option":"Magnesium oxide","bool":false},{"option":"All of these can be used","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium bicarbonate","bool":true},{"option":"Milk of magnesia","bool":false},{"option":"Limewater","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following blood vessels return blood from the body to the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Left main coronary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Aorta and superior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Aorta and pulmonary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary artery and inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava and inferior vena cava","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Peripheral cyanosis occurs in which of the following pathologies?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Lung diseases","bool":false},{"option":"Low cardiac output","bool":true},{"option":"Congenital heart diseases (right to left shunt)","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which is the most common organism responsible for infective endocarditis?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus viridans","bool":false},{"option":"H. Influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Entrococcus","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The exact spot where the QRS meets the ST-segment is known as:","answers":[{"option":"J-point","bool":true},{"option":"U-wave","bool":false},{"option":"Osborne wave","bool":false},{"option":"QRS junction","bool":false},{"option":"S-point","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A term infant is born with a large ventricular septal defect. Which coronary heart disease is most commonly associated with ventricular septal defect?","answers":[{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":true},{"option":"Transposition of great vessel","bool":false},{"option":"Coarctation of Aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Patent ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is the hallmark feature of right sided heart failure?","answers":[{"option":"Enlarged Right ventricle on echocardiography","bool":false},{"option":"Pericardial effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiomegaly on chest X ray","bool":false},{"option":"Ankle and pretibial edema","bool":true},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A colorless, odorless volatile liquid that may acquire a yellowish tinge on exposure to air, with burning sour taste are the physical and chemical properties of which mineral acid?","answers":[{"option":"Sulphuric acid","bool":true},{"option":"Nitric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Oxalic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrochloric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Carbolic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 42-year-old man comes to the emergency department with a history of taking liquids for suicide purpose. His pulse rate is 92/min and blood pressure is 120 /70 mmhg. He also has ulceration around the mouth and tongue. His chest is full of crepts and has severely labored breathing. Which of the following is the most appropriate initial step in management?","answers":[{"option":"Blood pressure maintenance","bool":false},{"option":"Injection morphine","bool":false},{"option":"Airway maintenance","bool":false},{"option":"Airway, breathing and circulation establishment","bool":true},{"option":"Mouth wash and antacids","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which type of atrial septal defect (ASD) is commonly associated with atrioventricular (AV) canal defect?","answers":[{"option":"ASD primum","bool":true},{"option":"ASD sinus venosus","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"ASD coronary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"ASD secundum","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"On autopsy, internal aspects of the stomach show brown folds and hardened esophagus. The acid involved will be:","answers":[{"option":"Nicotinic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Acetic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Oxalic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Carbolic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Salicylic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 25-year-old man complains of sharp pain which increases on lying down and is relieved with sitting. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":true},{"option":"Non-ST segment elevation myocardial infarction (NSTEMI)","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic dissection","bool":false},{"option":"ST segment elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI)","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The nutmeg liver in congestive cardiac failure has gross changes. Which of the following is the most likely correct answer?","answers":[{"option":"Red bluish areas in sinusoids","bool":false},{"option":"Red brown pericentral zone","bool":true},{"option":"Red brown periportal zone","bool":false},{"option":"Tan gray brown pericardial zone","bool":false},{"option":"Pale yellow around central veins","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 25-year-old patient with difficulty in breathing is diagnosed to have congestive heart failure. He is found to have differences in right and left arm pulses, diminished femoral pulses and notching of ribs on X-ray. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Transposition of great vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral valve stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 50-year-old obese female complains about the shortness of breath after her trip to the USA. What is a possible diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Tension pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":true},{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Gastritis","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which one of the following is considered as the principal preventive population strategy for cardiac disease?","answers":[{"option":"Dietary & life style changes","bool":true},{"option":"Stress management","bool":false},{"option":"Safe cigarettes","bool":false},{"option":"Adequate sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Adequate physical activity","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Atrial septal defect is:","answers":[{"option":"A congenital, cyanotic defect between left and right atrium","bool":false},{"option":"A congenital, non-cyanotic defect between left and right ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"An acquired defect of mitral valve","bool":false},{"option":"A congenital, non-cyanotic defect between left and right atrium","bool":true},{"option":"Defect between ascending aorta and pulmonary artery","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these is the most common association with a patent ductus arteriosus?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Isolated","bool":true},{"option":"Patent foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the best method to prevent aspiration during gastric lavage in a comatose patient?","answers":[{"option":"Keeping the patient in a sitting position","bool":false},{"option":"Suction","bool":false},{"option":"Use of endotracheal tube prior to the lavage","bool":true},{"option":"Left lateral positioning","bool":false},{"option":"Keeping the head lower than the legs","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these terms best describe angiography?","answers":[{"option":"An ionizing radiation","bool":false},{"option":"A diagnosis","bool":false},{"option":"An imaging technique","bool":true},{"option":"A surgical procedure","bool":false},{"option":"A drug","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these terms best describe echocardiography?","answers":[{"option":"MRI of the heart","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan of the heart","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray of the heart","bool":false},{"option":"Eco of heart sounds","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound of the heart","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these EKG changes are characteristic of atrial fibrillation?","answers":[{"option":"Broad QRS complexes","bool":false},{"option":"Absent P waves and regular R-R intervals","bool":false},{"option":"Absent P waves and irregular R-R intervals","bool":true},{"option":"Progressive lengthening of the PR interval","bool":false},{"option":"Saw tooth shaped P waves","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the first step in the management of an unstable patient with atrial fibrillation?","answers":[{"option":"IV fluids","bool":false},{"option":"IV adenosine","bool":false},{"option":"IV amiodarone","bool":false},{"option":"IV nitrates","bool":false},{"option":"Immediate DC cardioversion","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the most common and serious side effect of nitrates?","answers":[{"option":"Xanthopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Pruritus","bool":false},{"option":"Tachycardia and arrythmia","bool":false},{"option":"Throbbing headache and postural hypotension","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperuricemia","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Why are nitrates preferred sublingually instead of the oral route?","answers":[{"option":"To improve patient compliance","bool":false},{"option":"To improve duration of action","bool":false},{"option":"To avoid cardiac circulation","bool":false},{"option":"To avoid first pass metabolism","bool":true},{"option":"To avoid systemic side effects","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which antihypertensive has an initial hypertensive effect due to alpha 2 actions on the peripheral vasculature?","answers":[{"option":"Methyldopa","bool":false},{"option":"Atenolol","bool":false},{"option":"Clonidine","bool":true},{"option":"Phenoxybenzamine","bool":false},{"option":"Captopril","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A researcher wants to establish the prevalence of tuberculosis in Karachi. Which study design is most suitable for this?","answers":[{"option":"Cohort study","bool":false},{"option":"Case report","bool":false},{"option":"Case control study","bool":false},{"option":"Case series","bool":false},{"option":"Cross-sectional study","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these is the best modality to confirm the diagnosis of mitral stenosis?","answers":[{"option":"Echocardiography","bool":true},{"option":"Clinical history","bool":false},{"option":"MRI scan","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":false},{"option":"Chest X-ray","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which vasodilator drug is incorrectly paired with its mechanism of action?","answers":[{"option":"Dilitiazem: Calcium channel blocker","bool":false},{"option":"Ivabradine: Sodium channel blocker","bool":false},{"option":"Isosorbide dinitrate: Increases cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"Metoprolol: Increases cAMP","bool":true},{"option":"Nicorandil: Opens potassium channels","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 69-year-old man presents with chronic fatigue. He is a known cause of hypertension and a chest X-ray reveals bilateral pulmonary edema with a prominent left heart border. In line with this, what is the most appropriate description for his heart?","answers":[{"option":"Normal heart","bool":false},{"option":"Eccentric hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Concentric hypertrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Dilated cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the most important clinical finding in the diagnosis of congenital heart diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Tachycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Heart murmur","bool":false},{"option":"Central cyanosis","bool":true},{"option":"Tachypnea","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral cyanosis","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these drugs can cause gynecomastia?","answers":[{"option":"Diazoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Hydralazine","bool":false},{"option":"Guanathedine","bool":false},{"option":"Reserpine","bool":true},{"option":"Eplerenone","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these is the most common cause of hypertrophic cardiomyopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Idiopathic","bool":false},{"option":"Mutation involving sarcomere proteins","bool":true},{"option":"Infection","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"Mutation involving cytoskeletal proteins","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 7-month-old infant presents with short stature. He is at the 5th percentile for both height and weight. On examination, his temperature is 102 degrees celsius, and he is also tachycardia and tachypneic. He has a history of recurrent infections but there is no complaint of diarrhea. What is the most likely underlying etiology?","answers":[{"option":"Protein calorie malnutrition","bool":true},{"option":"Congenital heart disease","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"In cardiothoracic bypass surgery, where does the blood go after passing through the venous reservoir?","answers":[{"option":"Venous pump","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygenator","bool":true},{"option":"Aortic pump","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic cannula","bool":false},{"option":"Cell saver","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the most common type of cardiomyopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Dilated cardiomyopathy","bool":true},{"option":"Arrythmogenic right ventricular dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Unclassified cardiomyopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 56-year-old male presents with abdominal pain and peripheral edema. On examination, there is hepatomegaly as well as a positive shifting dullness. What are all these signs most indicative of?","answers":[{"option":"Kidney failure","bool":false},{"option":"Malnutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Right sided heart failure","bool":true},{"option":"Left sided heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following routes of administration is not used for nitroglycerin?","answers":[{"option":"Buccal","bool":false},{"option":"Oral","bool":false},{"option":"Transdermal","bool":false},{"option":"Intramuscular","bool":true},{"option":"Lingual","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following drugs needs to be stopped if a woman is planning on conception?","answers":[{"option":"Labetalol","bool":false},{"option":"Methyldopa","bool":false},{"option":"Hydralazine","bool":false},{"option":"Furosemide","bool":false},{"option":"Captopril","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these is the most important diagnostic sound in the diagnosis of mitral stenosis?","answers":[{"option":"Mid diastolic rumbling murmur","bool":true},{"option":"Mid systolic click","bool":false},{"option":"Loud S2","bool":false},{"option":"Loud S1","bool":false},{"option":"Soft S2","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 30-year-old male presents to the office with a headache and heavy sweating. On examination, he is tachypneic and has increased blood pressure. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Hypertension secondary to pituitary adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pheochromocytoma","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertension secondary to renal disease","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension secondary to adrenal cortex pathology","bool":false},{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these organisms is involved in rheumatic fever?","answers":[{"option":"Group B streptococci","bool":false},{"option":"Group A streptococci","bool":true},{"option":"Staph aureus","bool":false},{"option":"E coli","bool":false},{"option":"Staph epidermidis","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 40-year-old male presents with complaints of increasing breathlessness, fatigue, and weakness for the last 2 months. He has a history of mediastinal Hodgkin lymphoma treated with radiation therapy 5 years ago. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Myocarditis secondary to viral infection","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Dilated cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Systolic heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive cardiomyopathy","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these types of antidotes combine with poisons to form new less toxic compounds?","answers":[{"option":"Universal antidotes","bool":false},{"option":"Chemical antidotes","bool":true},{"option":"Physical antidotes","bool":false},{"option":"Physiological antidotes","bool":false},{"option":"Chelating agents","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which anti-hypertensive drug is a short-acting agent that is given intravenously in hypertensive emergencies and works by releasing nitric oxide?","answers":[{"option":"Esmolol","bool":false},{"option":"Nifedipine","bool":false},{"option":"Clonidine","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium nitroprusside","bool":true},{"option":"Hydralazine","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which one of these is a modifiable risk factor for the prevention of cardiovascular diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Age","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":true},{"option":"Family history","bool":false},{"option":"Genetics","bool":false},{"option":"Gender","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these is a non-modifiable risk factor in the context of cardiovascular diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Family history","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these EKG characteristics define a third-degree atrioventricular block?","answers":[{"option":"Bradycardia with broad QRS complexes","bool":false},{"option":"AV dissociation and ventricular escape rhythm","bool":true},{"option":"Progressive increase in PR interval","bool":false},{"option":"Saw tooth shaped P waves","bool":false},{"option":"Absent P waves","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of these is the ideal position for performing a gastric lavage?","answers":[{"option":"Prone","bool":false},{"option":"Supine","bool":false},{"option":"Frowler's","bool":false},{"option":"Left lateral","bool":true},{"option":"Right lateral","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding a stab wound?","answers":[{"option":"In this injury bruising around the opening of the wound is seen","bool":true},{"option":"It may occur with a knife","bool":false},{"option":"It is a wedge shaped opening wound","bool":false},{"option":"It results from piercing with a pointed weapon","bool":false},{"option":"Its greatest dimension is depth","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding age and color of a bruise?","answers":[{"option":"Blue on day 4","bool":false},{"option":"Green on day 2","bool":false},{"option":"Yellow on day 7-12","bool":true},{"option":"Normal at 1 week","bool":false},{"option":"Depends on size and swelling","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is not a characteristic of an ideal homicidal poison?","answers":[{"option":"Cheap in price","bool":false},{"option":"Tasteless and odorless","bool":false},{"option":"Should resemble a natural disease","bool":false},{"option":"Easily available","bool":false},{"option":"Orally ingested","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"How many seconds does a normal PR interval last?","answers":[{"option":"0.30 sec","bool":false},{"option":"0.22 sec","bool":false},{"option":"0.28 sec","bool":false},{"option":"0.20 sec","bool":true},{"option":"0.32 sec","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is malignant hypertension characterized by?","answers":[{"option":"Subluxation of cardiac vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaline arteriosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Calcific aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic insufficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperplastic arteriosclerosis","bool":true}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the most common poison used to commit suicide in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"Organophosphates","bool":true},{"option":"Barbiturates","bool":false},{"option":"Kerosene oil","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium cyanide","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Digoxin is contraindicated in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Complete heart block","bool":true},{"option":"Congenital disease","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Angina","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the mechanism of action of milrinone?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibits phosphodiesterase V","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits phosphodiesterase II","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits phosphodiesterase III","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibits phosphodiesterase I","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits phosphodiesterase IV","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the mechanism of action of losartan?","answers":[{"option":"Blocks partial AT2 receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Blocks AT1 + AT2 receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Blocks AT1 receptors","bool":true},{"option":"Blocks AT2 receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Blocks partial AT1 receptors","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following works by blocking VLDL synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Neomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrate","bool":false},{"option":"Resin","bool":false},{"option":"Statin","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotinic acid","bool":true}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following drugs is associated with myalgias and gallstones?","answers":[{"option":"Colestipol","bool":false},{"option":"Biguanide","bool":false},{"option":"Statin","bool":false},{"option":"Clofibrate","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrate","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following tests should be prescribed before starting a patient on statins?","answers":[{"option":"ALT and AST","bool":true},{"option":"Red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Platelet","bool":false},{"option":"BUN","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following drugs will you prescribe primarily to reduce triglycerides?","answers":[{"option":"Ezetimibe","bool":false},{"option":"Statin","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrate","bool":true},{"option":"Neomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotinic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Volition (delay of gratification) is the measure of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Thought","bool":false},{"option":"Self-awareness","bool":false},{"option":"Action","bool":false},{"option":"Willpower","bool":true},{"option":"Behaviour","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which antiarrhythmic drug causes systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)-like reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Flecainamide","bool":false},{"option":"Procainamide","bool":true},{"option":"Propanalol","bool":false},{"option":"Quinidine","bool":false},{"option":"Lidocaine","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following types of pericarditis is caused by Dressler syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Purulent","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhagic","bool":false},{"option":"Granulomatous","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinous","bool":true},{"option":"Serous","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the mechanism of action of nitrates?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibit cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"Activate cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibit cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"Activate cGMP","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibit cAMP and cGMP","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is the acid used in vitriolage?","answers":[{"option":"HClO4","bool":false},{"option":"HCl","bool":false},{"option":"HBr","bool":false},{"option":"H2SO4","bool":true},{"option":"HNO3","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Where does papillary fibroelastoma occur?","answers":[{"option":"Right atrium anterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricles near the semilunar valves","bool":true},{"option":"Right ventricle posterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Left atrium anterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricle near the apex","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which one of the following is the primary malignant tumor of the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Angiosarcoma","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Rhabdomyoma","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoma","bool":false},{"option":"Myxoma","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A marble factory worker complains of cough and shortness of breath. He may have which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Silicosis","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Anthracosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bagassosis","bool":false},{"option":"Berylliosis","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Hypothyroidism is associated with the prolonged use of which anti-arrhythmic agent?","answers":[{"option":"Amiodarone","bool":true},{"option":"Propafenone","bool":false},{"option":"Flecainide","bool":false},{"option":"Procainamide","bool":false},{"option":"Lidocaine","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"An ethical review committee permission is necessary for most research studies. Which of the following research studies does not require permission?","answers":[{"option":"Case series","bool":false},{"option":"Cohort - retrospective","bool":false},{"option":"Cohort - prospective","bool":false},{"option":"Cross-sectional study","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic review","bool":true}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A patient has an abdominal aortic aneurysm that was found on abdominal examination. Aneurysms are dilation of blood vessels. Which of the following is true about aneurysms?","answers":[{"option":"They are always congenital","bool":false},{"option":"They are saccular in shape","bool":false},{"option":"They involve the intima, media, and adventitia","bool":true},{"option":"They involve the intima and media","bool":false},{"option":"They are fusiform in shape","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is a sublingual form of nitrate?","answers":[{"option":"Isosorbide mononitrate","bool":false},{"option":"Glyceryl trinitrate","bool":true},{"option":"Pentaerythritol tetranitrat","bool":false},{"option":"Amyl nitrate","bool":false},{"option":"Pentaglyceryl trinitrate","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is the best investigation for pericardial effusion?","answers":[{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Echocardiography","bool":true},{"option":"ECG","bool":false},{"option":"CXR","bool":false},{"option":"CT","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 55-year-old male presents to the outpatient department (OPD) with abdominal discomfort and swelling of his legs for the past two years. On physical examination, jugular venous pressure is raised even when sitting up. The liver is enlarged and tender. Which of the following is most likely to cause these?","answers":[{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Right-sided heart failure","bool":true},{"option":"Myocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Endocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Left-sided heart failure","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the recommended amount of exercise to prevent cardiovascular disease?","answers":[{"option":"60 minutes, 5 days/week","bool":false},{"option":"15 minutes, 5 days/week","bool":false},{"option":"20 minutes, 5 days/week","bool":false},{"option":"30 minutes, 5 days/week","bool":true},{"option":"10 minutes, 5 days/week","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which type of pulse is seen in cardiac tamponade?","answers":[{"option":"Pulsus deficens","bool":false},{"option":"Pulsus alterans","bool":false},{"option":"Pulsus paradoxus","bool":true},{"option":"Pulsus tremens","bool":false},{"option":"Pulsus parvus","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following has a decreased risk of cardiovascular disease?","answers":[{"option":"Animal fat","bool":false},{"option":"Saturated fats","bool":false},{"option":"Cheese","bool":false},{"option":"Butter","bool":false},{"option":"Polyunsaturated vegetable oil","bool":true}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What is the most prominent feature in rheumatic fever?","answers":[{"option":"Sydenham chorea","bool":false},{"option":"Pancarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Subcutaneous nodules","bool":false},{"option":"Erythema marginatum","bool":false},{"option":"Migratory polyarthritis","bool":true}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following properties enables the cardiac muscle to act as a syncytium?","answers":[{"option":"Ryanodine receptor","bool":false},{"option":"Intercalated disc","bool":true},{"option":"Sinoatrial node","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"G protein","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Hyperpolarization of the pacemaker potential is characterized by which of the following ion movements?","answers":[{"option":"Increased efflux for potassium","bool":true},{"option":"Influx of calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Efflux of sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Influx of potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Influx of sodium","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following can reduce the risk of sudden cardiac death in a patient with hypertrophic cardiomyopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Implantable cardioverter-defibrillator","bool":true},{"option":"Radiofrequency ablation","bool":false},{"option":"β-Adrenergic blocking agents","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular pacing","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol septal ablation","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 55-year-old woman presents to the emergency department with sudden onset of chest pain. An ECG shows ST-segment elevations in leads II, III, avF, V4, V5, and V6. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Anterolateral MI","bool":false},{"option":"Inferolateral MI","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior wall MI","bool":false},{"option":"Anteroseptal MI","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior wall MI","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"What medication should be avoided in a patient with both asthma and angina?","answers":[{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":true},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrates","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium channel blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Antihistamines","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 65-year-old man presents to the emergency department with sudden onset of chest pain radiating to his left arm. He is diaphoretic and short of breath. An ECG shows ST-segment elevation in the lateral leads. The patient is diagnosed with acute myocardial infarction involving the lateral wall. What is the most appropriate 'initial' management for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Percutaneous coronary intervention","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinolytic therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Morphine","bool":true}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"The modified Duke's criteria are used to classify the probability of infective endocarditis  (IE) as definitive or possible.  \r\nThe diagnosis of definitive IE according to Duke's criteria is made when which of the following options is fulfilled?","answers":[{"option":"≥ 1 major criterion PLUS ≥ 2 minor criteria","bool":false},{"option":"≥ 3 minor criteria","bool":false},{"option":"≥ 4 minor criteria","bool":false},{"option":"≥ 2 major criteria","bool":true},{"option":"≥ 1 major criterion PLUS ≥ 1 minor criterion","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of dizziness in patients younger than 65 years?","answers":[{"option":"Anxiety","bool":true},{"option":"Vasovagal syncope","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac syncope","bool":false},{"option":"Orthostatic hypotension","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid sinus sensitivity","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of syncope in the general population?","answers":[{"option":"Vasovagal (Neurally mediated; reflex) syncope","bool":true},{"option":"Micturition syncope","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac syncope","bool":false},{"option":"Orthostatic hypotension","bool":false},{"option":"Anxiety","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"A 64-year-old male with hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy and a previous history of MI presents to the clinic with a complaint of recurrent syncope. Echocardiogram shows an increase in left ventricular wall thickness from last year. \r\nWhich of the following is the most suitable option to prevent sudden cardiac death in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Diltiazem","bool":false},{"option":"Implantable cardioverter-defibrillator (ICD)","bool":true},{"option":"Digoxin","bool":false},{"option":"β-blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Septal ablation","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of sudden cardiac death?","answers":[{"option":"Long QT syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Severe electrolyte abnormalities","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular tachycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular fibrillation","bool":true}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/cardiovascular/2021","question":"Which of the following is most appropriate for the treatment of bradycardia?","answers":[{"option":"Intravenous atropine","bool":true},{"option":"Intravenous adenosine","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Verapamil","bool":false},{"option":"Pralidoxime","bool":false}]}]
export default arr